To create a 3-tier environment I am using Terraform and Azure DevOps, below are the steps:

1. Create a new Azure DevOps project.
2. Create a Git intialized folder in you local system for Terraform code so later we can push the same in  Azure DevOps Repos project.
3. Write Terraform code to define the infrastructure resources, such as Application Gateway, virtual networks, virtual machines (App and DB VM's), subnet and so on.
4. Once IaC completed, we commit and push th code to Azure DevOps so that we will create the Build(CI) Pipeline and generate the artifact.
5. We will use the artifact in Deployement (CD) Pipeline to deploy the required infratucture.